<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The voice of Michael the archangel, to his Highness the Lord Protector: for the salvation of himself and the three nations. / Presented by Arise Evans.</title>
            <author>Evans, Arise, b. 1607.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1653</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 57 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 17 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A84161</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E3472</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E1480_2</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R208736</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99867659</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99867659</idno>
            <idno type="VID">119980</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A84161)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 119980)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 190:E1480[2])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The voice of Michael the archangel, to his Highness the Lord Protector: for the salvation of himself and the three nations. / Presented by Arise Evans.</title>
                  <author>Evans, Arise, b. 1607.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 27, [3] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Printed 1653. or as the vulgar think it, 1654.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "nouemb: 27.".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Cromwell, Oliver --  1599-1658 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Commonwealth and Protectorate, 1649-1660 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12</date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:119980:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:119980:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>THE VOICE OF MICHAEL THE Archangel, To his Highneſs The Lord PROTECTOR: For the Salvation of himſelf and the three Nations.</p>
            <p>Preſented by ARISE EVANS.</p>
            <q>
               <p>Thus ſaith the Lord, Stand ye in the ways, and ſee and ask after the old paths, where is the good way; and walk therein, and ye ſhall finde reſt for your ſouls; but they ſaid, we will not walk therein, <bibl>
                     <hi>Jer. 6.16.</hi>
                  </bibl>
               </p>
               <p>Alſo I ſet watchmen over you, ſaying, Hearken to the ſound of the trumpet: but they ſaid, We will not hearken, <bibl>
                     <hi>Verſ. 17.</hi>
                  </bibl>
               </p>
            </q>
            <p>Printed 1653. or as the vulgar think it, 1654.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:119980:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:119980:2"/>
            <opener>
               <salute>May it pleaſe your Highneſs,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">M</seg>Y <hi>Lord,</hi> your own words deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered, <hi>Sep.</hi> 12. as your ſpeech <hi>page</hi> 36. ſheweth, that ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times there is a neceſſity for a <hi>man</hi> to ſpeak, and that <hi>pure</hi> neceſſity hath no <hi>law:</hi> I would there were no cauſe for me, af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter I had ſpoken ſo much for you, to the diſcon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tentment of all my friends, <hi>and alſo to you, all for your advantage.</hi> If you had followed mine adviſe, according to the <hi>propheſying of God</hi> in your <hi>behalf,</hi> as you have it in all my <hi>books,</hi> ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cially in my <hi>book,</hi> called your <hi>Vindication.</hi> I ſay I would there were no cauſe for me to have <hi>expoſtulated</hi> theſe things with you <hi>now,</hi> and in ſuch a manner as <hi>this is;</hi> ſeeing I have ſo often by writting and printing ſhewed what by <hi>right</hi> you ſhould do.</p>
            <p>And as this <hi>twelve moneths</hi> I have been, <hi>ſo</hi> I am now kept off, by them that attend <hi>you,</hi> from having ſuch <hi>conſerence</hi> with you, as heretofore I had; and therefore I am forced to <hi>print</hi> what I would have but ſpoke or write, hoping it may come <hi>to your hands, and thence to your heart;</hi> yet leaving out ſomething, which in private might be <hi>phyſical unto you,</hi> becauſe I dare not commit <hi>them</hi> to the <hi>Preſs,</hi> and ſo make <hi>them</hi> ſubject to fooliſh cenſures.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:119980:3"/>
            <p>My <hi>Lord,</hi> It was no ſmall grief unto me, when I hard <hi>that</hi> which befell you laſt Saint <hi>Michaels</hi> day, though ſome to comfort me, ſaid, that it made <hi>much</hi> for me, becauſe, <hi>ſaid they,</hi> therein <hi>God</hi> hath appeared to maintaine my affirmati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, and to conſute your <hi>high aſſertions,</hi> in your ſpeech lately publiſhed. All <hi>glay</hi> be to <hi>God</hi> who did ſpeak to you in this time of <hi>need,</hi> though by a <hi>thunder.</hi> I would not declare it, if I knew a better <hi>interpreter</hi> that would deal more <hi>faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully</hi> with you concerning it, then I ſhall do; <hi>for I believe,</hi> though I be but a mean inſtrument, yet I am appointed of <hi>God</hi> to tell you, that it was <hi>Gods</hi> love to <hi>rebuke you,</hi> and it was his mercy to <hi>ſave you,</hi> and good <hi>may</hi> come to you of it. If you deſire to underſtand what is <hi>Gods meaning</hi> by it, <hi>I anſwer,</hi> his minde is, That you <hi>turn</hi> from your <hi>own deſignes</hi> NOW, and do <hi>Gods deſigns;</hi> GODS DESIGNE is made known unto you <hi>already</hi> by <hi>my books;</hi> that is, briefly, to ſtabliſh <hi>King Charles,</hi> and the true <hi>Religion;</hi> I mean <hi>Biſhops</hi> as we had before, <hi>and for that end God ſaved you.</hi> Your own <hi>deſigne</hi> is made known alſo, by your going about to do the <hi>contrary,</hi> for which cauſe <hi>God rebuked you.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And I pray you conſider it, <hi>God</hi> did not ſpeak to you in <hi>an unknown tongue,</hi> nor deny all your <hi>aſſertions</hi> (wherein you call <hi>him</hi> to witneſs) in a <hi>language</hi> that you cannot underſtand, <hi>and there was much of his love to you in that,</hi> Iſa. 28.11. but he anſwered you by your own <hi>words.</hi> For where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as you ſay, <hi>p.</hi> 37. of your ſpeech, That you could ſooner be willing to be <hi>rolled</hi> into your grave and buried with infamy, <hi>then</hi> part with that <hi>government</hi> which did eſtabliſh you a <hi>ſupreme;</hi> I pray conſider whether you were not <hi>rolled</hi> very
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:119980:3"/>neer your grave, ſo that a little more had done it. <hi>Behold</hi> it is hereby clear <hi>God</hi> diſowns your <hi>government,</hi> and your being ſet up by <hi>him;</hi> and they whom <hi>once</hi> ye counted the good people <hi>ſay as much,</hi> and them who ye counted the bad people <hi>ſay no leſs:</hi> who then is for ye, but a ſort of lukewarm <hi>people,</hi> that will turn with every winde? and what <hi>truſt</hi> can you re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe in them? <hi>Oh lay theſe things to heart,</hi> and know that <hi>God</hi> hath <hi>told you</hi> by this alſo, as I have <hi>told you often by writing,</hi> and will you not <hi>yet</hi> hear? Oh take heed leſt the trumpet of <hi>God</hi> wax louder and louder, <hi>Exod.</hi> 19.19. untill you be forced to <hi>hear.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>My <hi>Lord,</hi> I have no pleaſure in telling you theſe things, but it is <hi>needful</hi> I ſhould do it, for I finde men, yea <hi>Ministers,</hi> and your <hi>own</hi> too, <hi>do not</hi> deal faithfully with you; <hi>it is true,</hi> they tell you of ſin in general termes, and give <hi>hints</hi> alſo in publike of this <hi>very</hi> judgement before all men to your diſhoner; <hi>yet</hi> they do not examine the cauſe why, and ſhew you for what great <hi>ſin</hi> this threatning hand of <hi>God</hi> appeared againſt you. The Magicians dealt not ſo with <hi>Pharaoh</hi> when they ſaw <hi>God</hi> appear for <hi>Iſrael,</hi> but told him plainly, <hi>This is the finger of God,</hi> Exod. 8.19. And how doth <hi>Joſhua</hi> take on, when he ſaw the judgement of <hi>God</hi> upon them; and what en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiry doth he make untill he found out the <hi>ſin</hi> which was the <hi>cauſe</hi> of it? <hi>Joſh.</hi> 7. Yea, the very <hi>heathen</hi> were <hi>ſo troubled</hi> when they ſaw a ſudden tempeſt come upon them, that ſearch is made with all ſpeed to finde out <hi>the ſin and cauſe of it,</hi> Jon. 1.4, 5, 6, 7, 8.</p>
            <p>And how was <hi>Pharaoh</hi> troubled with his <hi>dream</hi> untill he found out an <hi>interpreter?</hi> and what
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:119980:4"/>great benefit came unto <hi>him</hi> by knowing the truth of it, <hi>Gen.</hi> 41. And what a ſtir <hi>Nebuchad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nezzar</hi> kept about his <hi>dream,</hi> though he had <hi>forget it,</hi> ſo that he would have deſtroyed all his <hi>wiſemen,</hi> becauſe they could not tell him both his <hi>dream</hi> and the <hi>interpretation</hi> thereof, had not <hi>Daniel</hi> anſwered his <hi>expectation,</hi> and who can blame him for it? <hi>the matter is worthy of all that ſeeking after,</hi> Dan. 2. was not alſo <hi>Belſhazzar</hi> troubled when be had prophaned and diſhonor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed <hi>Gods holy veſſels,</hi> and ſaw his ſentence of <hi>death</hi> written before him on the wall, was not he troubled for an <hi>interpreter to open it?</hi> Dan. 5. and though the <hi>news</hi> to him was <hi>bad,</hi> yet how <hi>gloriouſly</hi> doth he reward <hi>Daniel</hi> according to the manner of the two former <hi>Kings!</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And <hi>David</hi> had his <hi>Prophets,</hi> that told <hi>him</hi> of his particular <hi>ſin,</hi> and he gladly heard <hi>them,</hi> and was obedient, 2 <hi>Sam.</hi> 12. 2 <hi>Sam.</hi> 24. and when a judgement came, <hi>David</hi> enquired <hi>him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf</hi> for to know the <hi>cauſe</hi> of it, 2 <hi>Sam.</hi> 21.1. but ſee the contrary <hi>ſpirit; Amaziah,</hi> though ſometimes a good <hi>King;</hi> yet when the <hi>Prophet</hi> told him of his particular <hi>ſin,</hi> he could not en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dure <hi>him,</hi> 2 Chron. 25.2.7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17. And <hi>Herod</hi> gladly heard <hi>John Bap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſt,</hi> and did many things as he would have <hi>him do;</hi> but when <hi>John</hi> comes to deal faithfully with <hi>him,</hi> and told <hi>him</hi> of his own darling <hi>ſin,</hi> which by no means he could endure <hi>to hear of;</hi> then <hi>John</hi>'s head muſt be taken off, rather then <hi>Herod</hi> would part with his ſin, <hi>Mark</hi> 6.17, 18, 20.27.</p>
            <p>Therefore my <hi>Lord,</hi> blame me not, though I deal faithfully with you; <hi>God</hi> ſpeaks by <hi>viſions</hi> once, yea twice, and man perceiveth it not;
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:119980:4"/>then GOD is gracious, ſends an <hi>interpreter</hi> (one choſen from among a thouſand) to ſhew <hi>man</hi> his way, and to keep him from the <hi>pit,</hi> Job. 33.14, 15.23.24. For a <hi>man</hi> in a great <hi>ſin,</hi> is as one in a deep ſleep <hi>over a pit;</hi> and though God ſpeaks aloud to <hi>him,</hi> he cannot hear, for the ſweet <hi>rest</hi> that he takes in his <hi>proſperity,</hi> and <hi>ſin</hi> will <hi>hardly</hi> ſuffer <hi>him</hi> to awake before he falleth into the <hi>pit,</hi> and then it is too late. It is a great <hi>grace</hi> for a man, when he is told of his particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar <hi>ſin, not to deny it,</hi> but to <hi>confeſs it and forſake it,</hi> Prov. 28.13. How ſweet a thing it is to ſee <hi>Davids</hi> Confeſſion, when <hi>Nathan</hi> had taken him as in a <hi>net,</hi> by making him pronounce Judgement a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt himſelf, 2 <hi>Sam.</hi> 12.13. And how grievous a thing it is to ſee a <hi>man</hi> hardned like <hi>Pharaoh</hi> in his ſin, when his <hi>own</hi> Magicians tell him, <hi>Exod.</hi> 8.9. <hi>This is the finger of God.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Oh my Lord, <hi>God</hi> hath ſpoken <hi>once</hi> or <hi>twice</hi> to you, let him ſpeak no more to you after this manner, leſt you ſmart to the purpoſe for it, I am ſure he hath a part in you that he will not looſe; he will put you to the greateſt afflicti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons that ever was in the world, <hi>yea beyond Jobs,</hi> rather then you ſhall go <hi>on</hi> in your <hi>ſin. Oh then return at this one voice,</hi> as <hi>Saint Paul did,</hi> who a little before was as reſolute to the contrary as you can be. I know my <hi>Lord</hi> you are wiſe, and exceeding wiſe, and that by your <hi>wiſdome</hi> you think to ſtand; glory not in it, but know this, that <hi>God takes the wiſe in their own craftineſs,</hi> Job 5.11, 12, 13, 14, 15. 1 Corin. 3.19, 20. There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore do not think, or ſay within your ſelf, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe I am wiſe, I am rich, I am ſtrong, <hi>Jer.</hi> 9.23. I will go on to keep out ſuch a party; be not deceived any longer, <hi>for God is wiſer, ſtronger, and
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:119980:5"/>richer then you,</hi> he knoweth wherefore he hath <hi>deſigned you.</hi> And though he ſuffered you to go <hi>on</hi> with proſperity <hi>thus far,</hi> and you think it is pleaſing to <hi>God,</hi> yet you will finde it is not ſo.</p>
            <p>I do verily believe that your <hi>Speech</hi> came from your heart, and you thought <hi>God</hi> went along with you all this time, for <hi>God did foreſee,</hi> that an eminent man ſhould have a ſtrong erring confidence (as once <hi>Paul</hi> had) being utterly de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived <hi>in his thoughts of God,</hi> at the time when he came to <hi>judgement,</hi> and therefore hear what he ſaith, <hi>Pſal.</hi> 50.4, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23. <hi>But unto the wicked God ſaith, What haſt thou to do to declare my Statutes, or that thou ſhouldeſt take my Covenant in thy mouth? ſeeing thou hateſt inſtruction, and caſteſt my words behinde thee? When thou ſaweſt a thief, then thou conſentedſt with him, and haſt been partaker with adulterers. Thou giveſt thy mouth to evil, and thy tongue frameth de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceit. Thou ſitteſt and ſpeakeſt againſt thy brother, and ſlandereſt thine own mothers ſon. Theſe things haſt thou done, and I kept ſilence: thou thoughteſt that I was altogether ſuch a one as thy ſelf: but I will reprove thee, and ſet them in order before thine eyes.</hi> Now conſider this, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="1">1. Mark my <hi>Lord,</hi> Pſal. 50.16, 17. <hi>He tells</hi> of your preſumption in declaring his <hi>Statutes,</hi> as if you were called to do it; and of your caſting away behind you his inſtruction, and his true <hi>Miniſters</hi> who are lawfully <hi>called,</hi> and enabled to declare to you the truth perfectly, even the <hi>Miniſters</hi> of the <hi>Church</hi> of <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="2">2. Mark my <hi>Lord,</hi> verſ. 18. <hi>He tells</hi> you how you conſent with thoſe theeviſh <hi>Kings,</hi> who like <hi>Nimrod,</hi> Gen. 10.9. think it is lawful for
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:119980:5"/>them to take what they can get by the <hi>ſword;</hi> and of your partaking with men in ſpiritual a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dultery, or falſe worſhipping of <hi>God.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="3">3. Mark my <hi>Lord, verſ.</hi> 19. <hi>He tells</hi> you this, <hi>Thou giveſt thy mouth to evil, and thy tongue fram<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth deceit,</hi> that is againſt <hi>God,</hi> the <hi>King,</hi> and the <hi>Church,</hi> and yet you thinke it is not ſo.</p>
            <p n="4">4. Mark my <hi>Lord,</hi> v. 20. <hi>He tells</hi> you of your ſitting in State, and wronging the <hi>King,</hi> who is the ſon of your <hi>true</hi> and onely mother, the <hi>Church of England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="5">5. Mark my <hi>Lord, He tells</hi> you, that God did let you go on all this time, and ſay nothing to all that you did; wherefore you never <hi>doubted,</hi> but thought ſurely, <hi>God</hi> in a more extraordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry manner was with you and your army, <hi>then</hi> he was with any people on earth, as your ſpeech ſhews, <hi>page</hi> 37. therefore he tells you, that you are miſtaken <hi>in your thoughts of God,</hi> and that you are adverſe before him in your works <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>ch he ſets in order before your eyes; that he <hi>now</hi> will let you know his minde, and reprove you indeed, and tear you in pieces, except you or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der your converſation aright, <hi>verſe</hi> 22, 23. and make your peace as <hi>Zacheus</hi> did, <hi>Luk.</hi> 19.8.</p>
            <p>My <hi>Lord,</hi> thus righteous <hi>David,</hi> or rather <hi>God</hi> ſmites you, <hi>that you might turn to him,</hi> Pſal. 141.5. Iſa. 9.13. Doubt not but that I give you the true meaning of <hi>Pſal.</hi> 50. and that you are the perſon there ſignified, <hi>verſ.</hi> 21. For I have the <hi>ſpirit</hi> that <hi>David</hi> had, becauſe he and I was <hi>anointed</hi> together; and I believe that you will ſay that you have <hi>ſeen</hi> ſome of the effects of my <hi>anointing</hi> by my propheſying, which already have been fulfilled.</p>
            <pb n="8" facs="tcp:119980:6"/>
            <p>And to prove my <hi>anointing,</hi> look in 1 <hi>Sam.</hi> 16. verſ. 3. (ſaith God to <hi>Samuel) thou ſhalt a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noint unto me, him, whom I name unto thee,</hi> verſ. 11. (<hi>Samuel</hi> ſaith to <hi>Jeſſe) ſend and fetch him, for we will not ſit down till he come hither,</hi> verſ. 12. (the Lord names me, and bids him anoint me, as you ſee) <hi>And the Lord ſaid, Ariſe, anoint him, for this is he.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now <hi>obſerve,</hi> according to the command and promiſe, <hi>verſ.</hi> 3. <hi>Thou ſhalt anoint him whom I name,</hi> verſ. 12. he doth not name <hi>David,</hi> but <hi>ariſe;</hi> and if you obſerve, the <hi>holy word</hi> takes off <hi>all objections;</hi> and leſt ſome ſhould ſay, <hi>God</hi> bide <hi>Samuel</hi> who was ſat down, <hi>ariſe</hi> to anoint <hi>David,</hi> therefore ſaith <hi>Samuel</hi> to take off that conceit, <hi>verſ.</hi> 11. <hi>We will not ſit down till he come hither,</hi> ſo that it is clear; that as <hi>David</hi> was <hi>anointed</hi> with <hi>oile,</hi> as you ſee by the <hi>Hiſtory:</hi> ſo I was <hi>anointed</hi> by the <hi>ſpirit,</hi> as you ſee by the <hi>myſtery,</hi> and by many other places I could prove it; therefore I believe that I have as good <hi>authority</hi> to do what I do, as any man hath; and I hope my <hi>Lord</hi> you will not deſpiſe it, though per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haps many (whoſe caſe is miſerable) that have not taſted of the heavenly gift, <hi>Heb.</hi> 6.4. nor known the quickning power and operation of the work of God upon their ſouls, <hi>Heb.</hi> 4.12, 13. 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 15.45. will both deſpiſe it and reject it.</p>
            <p>Now my <hi>Lord</hi> I ſee, and you may ſee, that you have been miſtaken in <hi>God,</hi> and in his <hi>Church</hi> all this while; for it is <hi>Gods</hi> time to help his people, <hi>when all their power is gone,</hi> ſo that there is none ſhut up or left, <hi>Deut.</hi> 32.34, 35, 36. and nor afore. Then ſheweth God his power to ſave his <hi>Church;</hi> and therefore do not think,
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:119980:6"/>that though <hi>God</hi> ſuffered men <hi>thus far</hi> to tread down his <hi>Church,</hi> and to do to them what they pleaſed: but that <hi>God</hi> now will <hi>remember</hi> and ſave them: <hi>Herod</hi> for a time vexed the <hi>Church,</hi> and he killed <hi>James;</hi> and becauſe he ſaw that it pleaſed the wicked Jews (as now it pleaſeth the Presbyters to ſee <hi>an Ordinance</hi> come forth to afflict our <hi>Miniſters</hi>) he laid hold on <hi>Peter,</hi> thinking utterly to deſtroy the <hi>Miniſters,</hi> hoping that then the pillars being down, the Church would fall of it ſelf. But in this time of ſtraight<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, the <hi>Lord</hi> ſends his angel to deliver <hi>Peter</hi> and the <hi>Church,</hi> and to deſtroy <hi>Herod,</hi> Acts 12.1, 2, 3.11.23.24. and then the Church flouriſhed.</p>
            <p>Truly my <hi>Lord,</hi> you ſhall finde that I am faithful to you; you are not the firſt that was deceived after this manner: but I finde <hi>none</hi> ſo like you as <hi>Saint Paul</hi> was, who breathing out threatnings and ſlaughter againſt the Diſciples of the <hi>Lord,</hi> in the hight of his perſecuting <hi>zeal,</hi> fell to the earth <hi>a Phariſee,</hi> but roſe a Chriſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>an, <hi>Act.</hi> 9. Oh it was a good fall to <hi>him,</hi> and ſo I hope your fall will be to you. Poor man! the very <hi>light</hi> that he ſaw from his fall, ſtruck him blinde, ſo that he was willing to receive his ſight of him whom Chriſt had appointed to give it him, though a man without any out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward call to do it. So I truſt you will receive your <hi>ſpiritual ſight</hi> of me, who am not appointed of the Miniſters, but of <hi>God</hi> alone to do it: the <hi>paralel</hi> holds in all things, and therefore be ſure that it is of God, and it is his will for your ſalva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, that you <hi>now</hi> ſhould <hi>hear</hi> me. And this I ſay unto you, that as Saint <hi>Paul</hi> was <hi>Jeſus Chriſts chief Champion</hi> for his warfare, ſo ſhall you be
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:119980:7"/>
               <hi>King Charles chief Champion</hi> for his warfare, and all to the glory of JESUS CHRIST. For there is but one juſt <hi>war</hi> in the world; and that <hi>war</hi> is for the firſt born of <hi>Japhet, the elder ſon of Noah,</hi> Gen. 10.2, 3, 4, 5.21. which is in the world. How to finde out this man, by his Genealogies, it is impoſſible, 1 <hi>Tim.</hi> 1.4. And therefore God pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſeth to give teſtimony of him to the world, as he gave teſtimony of his own ſon <hi>Jeſus Chriſt,</hi> by giving a day-ſtar alſo at his birth, <hi>Rev.</hi> 2.27, 28. and as the Star was taken notice of at <hi>Chriſts birth:</hi> ſo muſt this Star be taken notice of, <hi>at this mans birth,</hi> as <hi>Saint Peter</hi> ſaith, 2 <hi>Pet.</hi> 1.19. take heed to the <hi>day-ſtar;</hi> and ſo much notice was taken of it, that there was Latin Verſes made of it, and preſented to the late <hi>King Charles,</hi> as followeth.</p>
            <q>
               <l>Rex ubi Paulinas acceſſit gratus ad aras,</l>
               <l>Immicuit medio lucida ſtella Pole.</l>
               <l>Dic divina mihi tractasn aenigmata caeli,</l>
               <l>Haec Oriens nobis, quid ſibi ſtella velit?</l>
               <l>Magnus in Occiduo principes modo naſcitur orbe,</l>
               <l>Moxque ſub eclipſi regna Orientis erunt.</l>
            </q>
            <p>Engliſhed thus by Mr. <hi>J. B.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>
               <l>When to <hi>Pauls</hi> croſs the grateful <hi>King</hi> drew neer,</l>
               <l>A ſhining ſtar did in the heaven appear.</l>
               <l>Thou that conſults with divine myſteries,</l>
               <l>Tell me what this bright Comet ſignifies:</l>
               <l>Now is there born a valiant Prince i'th' Weſt,</l>
               <l>That ſhall ecliſpe the Kingdomes of the Eaſt.</l>
            </q>
            <p>And this man hath as true, and more autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ity over all the world, be they <hi>Kings,</hi> or of
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:119980:7"/>whatſoever degree they be, then any man or <hi>King</hi> hath over his own children; and as he is bound to rule them ſeverely in righteouſneſs, ſo every one alſo is bound upon pain of <hi>eternal damnation,</hi> Rom. 13.2. to aſſiſt him againſt all ſuch Rebels as ſhall oppoſe him; and there is great need of ſuch a <hi>King</hi> to be over all the <hi>Kings</hi> in the world, to puniſh them <hi>that quarel and are rebellious to Gods word,</hi> for Kings com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monly are as other wicked <hi>men</hi> be <hi>that fear not God:</hi> tell them of <hi>Jeſus Chriſt,</hi> and that he will puniſh them at the day of Judgement; <hi>alas</hi> they matter not that, <hi>that</hi> never hinders them, no more then it doth hinder a <hi>thief</hi> from ſtealing. And as there is many <hi>theeves,</hi> yea moſt men are ſo minded they would <hi>ſteal,</hi> if it were not for fear of the <hi>gallows,</hi> which <hi>fear</hi> doth reſtrain <hi>them;</hi> ſo theſe <hi>theeviſh</hi> minded <hi>Kings</hi> of the earth, If there were <hi>one</hi> to puniſh them here, they would <hi>fear him,</hi> and not do wickedly; and he would be as <hi>terrible</hi> to the wicked <hi>kings</hi> of the earth, <hi>Pſal.</hi> 76.12. as the <hi>gallows</hi> is for a <hi>theev<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing minded</hi> man, who would <hi>ſteal,</hi> but dare not for fear the <hi>gallows</hi> catch him; for as in <hi>Jeſus Chriſt God</hi> ſhewed the excellency of his <hi>mercy</hi> to mankinde; ſo <hi>in this man God</hi> ſheweth forth the excellency of his <hi>juſtice to mankinde,</hi> without which <hi>juſtice</hi> good peaceable men nor <hi>Kings</hi> cannot be <hi>perfectly</hi> happy.</p>
            <p>Therefore, you that will draw the ſword, draw it for <hi>King Charles;</hi> all that draw it other ways, draw it for <hi>Nimrod:</hi> and <hi>Nimrods</hi> cauſe and te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>net was this ſaying, <hi>Becauſe I am ſtronger then my neighbour, brother, or father, therefore it is lawful for me to kill him, and take all that he hath:</hi> and if you ſay unto <hi>Nimrod,</hi> You muſt do unto all
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:119980:8"/>men as you would have all men do unto you, he will anſwer, ſo I will, <hi>For I would have any man, if he can, to kill me, and take all from me; there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I do no more to them then I would have them do to me, if they dare.</hi> And by this rule and law Princes go to this day, and ſo the world is diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quieted: therefore <hi>God</hi> ſaith (meaning <hi>Charles</hi> and his line for ever) <hi>He ſhall cut off the ſpirit of Princes, he ſhall be terrible to the Kings of the earth,</hi> Pſal. 76.12. that is, to ſuch unjuſt <hi>princes</hi> and <hi>Kings,</hi> that live by the ſword, and not by righteouſneſs.</p>
            <p>All warriers ſhould take <hi>Abraham</hi> for their pattern, becauſe he is the firſt <hi>holy warrier</hi> we read off. And mark what the <hi>prophet</hi> ſaith of <hi>Abraham</hi> and of <hi>Chriſt</hi> to you ſouldiers, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 51.1, 2. <hi>Hearken to me ye that follow after righteouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, ye that ſeek the Lord, look unto the rook whence ye are hewn, and to the hole of the pit whence ye are digged, look unto</hi> Abraham <hi>your father, and unto</hi> Sarah (the Church) <hi>that bare you: for I have called him alone, and bleſſed him, and increaſed him.</hi> And again ſaith our Saviour, <hi>John</hi> 8.39. <hi>If ye were</hi> Abrahams <hi>children, ye would do the works of Abraham.</hi> Now look what <hi>Abraham</hi> did in his matter <hi>of war: Abraham</hi> went out to help <hi>Lot</hi> a juſt man, who was taken captive, and robbed of all that he had (a juſt cauſe) <hi>Abra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>braham</hi> had but his own houſhold, being three hundred men, and a few neighbors with him, to go againſt five Kings, that had put four Kings to flight, and <hi>conquered</hi> all the countries round about them. <hi>Abraham</hi> with his men over-takes theſe gallant <hi>Kings,</hi> cuts them <hi>down</hi> with al their hoaſt, and brings home <hi>Lot,</hi> with all the goods and perſons that they had taken from <hi>Sodom;</hi>
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:119980:8"/>and though the <hi>King</hi> of <hi>Sodom,</hi> who was ſure a wicked man, <hi>Gen.</hi> 13.13. deſired of him but the perſons onely, yet <hi>Abraham</hi> did give him all his goods alſo to a ſhoo-latchet, <hi>Gen.</hi> 14.</p>
            <p>Hear is a great <hi>conqueror,</hi> yet he doth not go about to diſ-inherite the children of thoſe wick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed <hi>Kings</hi> he had ſlain, he gives all the goods that they had taken, to the true owners <hi>again;</hi> he is no way ambitious to follow the war to make himſelf <hi>great;</hi> for ſurely he might ſoon have <hi>conquered the world,</hi> after the rate that he went for that little <hi>time.</hi> No, he would live private<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly in the ſervice of <hi>God,</hi> onely he would ſhew them that are ſouldiers an <hi>example,</hi> how they ſhould behave themſelves in their <hi>ſtation,</hi> but few follow his <hi>example,</hi> ſpecially in our days, yet they would be counted <hi>bleſſed,</hi> and <hi>Saints</hi> as well as <hi>he;</hi> but <hi>God</hi> will let them ſtay for the <hi>bleſſing</hi> of <hi>Abraham,</hi> untill they ſhew forth the works of <hi>Abraham.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And immediately after <hi>Abraham</hi> had ſhewed his faith to the glory of <hi>God,</hi> by doing theſe righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teous actions before all the world: mark what followeth, <hi>Gen.</hi> 15.1. <hi>Then the word of the Lord came unto him in a viſion, ſaying, Fear not Abra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham, I am thy ſheild and thy exceeding great re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward,</hi> and this reward <hi>Abraham</hi> valued above all the world. Oh it is wonderful to ſee how well <hi>God</hi> is pleaſed with <hi>Abraham:</hi> upon this <hi>God</hi> comes to be more acquainted with <hi>Abra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham,</hi> and tells him more of his <hi>counſel,</hi> gives him more of his <hi>love</hi> then he had before. And I pray obſerve, a body would have thought, that <hi>Abraham</hi> going out in ſo juſt a <hi>cauſe,</hi> and upon his own <hi>charge,</hi> That it had been <hi>lawful</hi> for <hi>him</hi> to get what he could from ſuch wicked <hi>Kings;</hi>
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:119980:9"/>and to ſerve them as they would have ſerved him, to take their poſſeſſions and diſ-inherite their children. No, <hi>Abraham</hi> did not count it lawful to rob the children of a theif and a mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therer, who had bought it at ſo dear a rate, that he had given his ſoul and body to eternal torments for <hi>an inheritance</hi> to his <hi>children: God forbid</hi> that any childe of <hi>God</hi> ſhould out-bid them, let them take it, ſaith <hi>Abraham:</hi> I will have none of their accurſed things. Here you ſee the works of <hi>Abraham;</hi> though he fought for it: <hi>he reſtored</hi> to every <hi>man</hi> his own again, he doth not go about to diſ-inherit any of what was theirs; he never examined how they came by their <hi>riches,</hi> but he looks to his own conſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence, leſt that ſhould be defiled; and ſee how God bleſſed him above all the men on earth.</p>
            <p>Oh my <hi>Lord,</hi> and all you noble ſouldiers, here is a fair <hi>example</hi> for you: do as <hi>Abraham</hi> did. If <hi>Abraham</hi> had been warring among us in your ſtead, <hi>King Charles</hi> had been on his throne afore now, and every man in his own in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>heritance by his birth-right; he would have had no <hi>Caterpillars</hi> to devour the land, ſuch as your Committees, Sequeſtrators and the like. Oh then do the works of <hi>Abraham</hi> (that ye may have the bleſſing of <hi>Abraham</hi>) by reſtoring <hi>King Charles</hi> and his party, whom ſo many <hi>Kings,</hi> even the late Parliament, purſued, and took all from him and his party: and God delivered the Parliament into your hands; now put the <hi>King</hi> and his <hi>party</hi> into their poſſeſſions a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain (though they be ſinners by your account, yet) they are not worſe then the <hi>Sodomites,</hi> and their <hi>King,</hi> to whom <hi>Abraham</hi> gave all again.</p>
            <p>You know you cannot have the bleſſing of
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:119980:9"/>
               <hi>Abraham.</hi> If you follow that curſed ſeed of <hi>Nimrod the mighty hunter before the Lord,</hi> Gen. 9.22.25. <hi>Gen.</hi> 10.6.8, 9, 10. <hi>Abraham</hi> will anſwer ſuch, though they have been the greateſt Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manders in the world of <hi>Nimrods</hi> ſide, worſe then he anſwered <hi>Dives,</hi> Luke 16. from verſe 20 to the end of the Chapter, yet that was bad enough, ſpecially to one that was his ſon, one that did no evil to no body: he did not ſend <hi>Lazarus</hi> away to <hi>Bridwell</hi> for asking alms: he might have gone where he would for him, but he would give him nothing, and becauſe of that he muſt go to hell: a hard caſe. Some ſay the Cavaliers go the way to hell; there is no ſuch matter, they ſee not right that ſay it, for ſince the caſe is thus with <hi>Dives,</hi> they are more liker to be the Presbyterians which go that way, for the Cavaliers are they that relieve the <hi>Lazarus</hi>'s of our times, and the Presbyterians do not onely deny theſe relief, but alſo afflict them ſore in <hi>Bridwells,</hi> and that is more then <hi>Dives</hi> did to <hi>Lazarus;</hi> therefore my <hi>Lord,</hi> judge you which of them <hi>twain</hi> go the way to hell. I have obſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved, that where the Scripture commonly is moſt in men by notion, there its leaſt in practice of charity, &amp; where it is leaſt in notion (for there is none but have ſome Scripture) there it is moſt in fruit of Charity; ſo that it is rare to finde a know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing man (as we call it) that is Charitable. And it is ſo indeed, for Saint <hi>Paul</hi> ſaith, 1 <hi>Corin.</hi> 8.1. <hi>Knowledge puffeth up, but Charity edifieth,</hi> and <hi>Mat.</hi> 15.8. <hi>This people draweth nigh to me with their mouths, and honor me with their lips, but their hearts are far from me.</hi> My <hi>Lord</hi> you ſhall finde the <hi>Kings</hi> party (though they ſlip into ſmall ſins) to be the beſt men in the kingdom, and that
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:119980:10"/>their reſolution (in matters of the greateſt con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cernment) is true and conſtant to God and man (as for your others, they are but bubbles) and that the ſubſtance of Chriſtian Religion doth not ſtand in notions, but in contrition, charity, and devotion: which things moſt abound among Cavaliers; therefore miſtake not the people of God.</p>
            <p>I have ſhewed you what you have to do, and how &amp; under whoſe <hi>banner</hi> ye ought to, <hi>war,</hi> and for what cauſe: now let me tell you, that God hath ſent his Angel to deliver us, and to be aſſiſtant unto you, if you go the right way, as I have ſhewed you ſufficiently already: but if you will not, the ſame <hi>angel</hi> will be your adverſary, <hi>Numb.</hi> 22.22. And who then that God will ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept, can or dare pray for you? I would not have you miſtake me; for though I be for <hi>Charles Steward</hi> in regard of righteouſneſs, if that line ſhould fail, ſo that we were to ſeek again, I had rather have you to <hi>raign</hi> (and the Cava<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liers are all ſo minded) then any man on earth beſides.</p>
            <p>Yet ſince, like <hi>Balaams Aſs,</hi> I carried you on ſafely to this day, Now God doth open my mouth to tell the danger I ſee in your way, for you have had a mind (being ſtirred up by the <hi>Balacks</hi> of our times) to curſe <hi>Iſrael,</hi> that is, to to afflict the Proteſtants and our Religion, but take heed what you do unto them, for the <hi>voice</hi> of a <hi>King</hi> is among them, <hi>Numb.</hi> 23.21. and the Angel of the Lord with his drawn ſword ſtands in your way, though yet you have taken no no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice of him; but I beſeech you again conſider ſeriouſly what befel you on Saint <hi>Michael</hi> the <hi>Archangels</hi> day laſt paſt, and know what an An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gel <hi>Michael</hi> is ſaid to be in Scripture.</p>
            <pb n="17" facs="tcp:119980:10"/>
            <p n="1">1. He is ſaid to be the chief Prince of war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like angels, <hi>Dan.</hi> 10.13. <hi>Rev.</hi> 12.7. and you know one angel is able to deſtroy in a moment of time, the greateſt and ſtouteſt army that ever was, witneſs <hi>Sennacheribs</hi> army, whereof there was of them deſtroyed by an angel in one night, a hundred fourſcore and five thouſand, 2 <hi>Kings</hi> 19.35.</p>
            <p n="2">2. <hi>Michael</hi> is ſaid to hold <hi>with the man cloa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thed in linnen,</hi> which gives you to underſtand that he is for the Surplice, and for the true worſhip of God, and not for confuſed vain janglings and bablings, <hi>Dan.</hi> 10.5.13.21.</p>
            <p n="3">3. He is alſo the Prince of the people of God, and their angel to protect them, againſt which people you have appeared much, to deſtroy them hitherto, <hi>Dan.</hi> 10.21.</p>
            <p>But take heed what ye do againſt the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teſtant <hi>Church</hi> hereafter; for ſince <hi>Michael</hi> is come (whom they ſo much acknowledge (as you may ſee by the Collect for that day) that they deſire God to ſuccor them, &amp; help them by his angels) And that <hi>Michael</hi> hath appeared ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to their prayer, and the promiſe, which is, that in the time of need, God ſhould ſend him to ſtand up for his people, <hi>Dan.</hi> 12.1. 1 <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 4.16. 2 <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 1.6, 7, 8, 9. I ſay again take heed, for though you be a terror to poor men, you are no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing in the hand of <hi>Michael</hi> the mighty Angel, who we believe will deliver us, and hath for that end ſhewed his hand againſt you the laſt <hi>Michaels</hi> day, to note to you by that day, and what befell you on it, that he is againſt you.</p>
            <p>But now you wil ask me, why do we take no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice of his day? I anſwer, Do not you take notice
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:119980:11"/>on <hi>Gregory</hi> or <hi>Magnus</hi> day, being <hi>Sept.</hi> 3. to be a good day for you? yet that day this yeer proved to be the <hi>Lords</hi> day; therefore I ſay ſince that you have ſuch eſtimation of <hi>Sept.</hi> 3. that though you do not keep it as an holy day, to worſhip <hi>God</hi> on it, yet you make it the chief day for your <hi>enterpriſe,</hi> why ſhould not we then having all our hopes in heaven, take no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice on <hi>Sept.</hi> 29. it being the <hi>Archangel Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaels</hi> day, ſet apart <hi>to worſhip</hi> God on, ſeeing he is the angel which God hath promiſed to ſend from <hi>heaven</hi> to deliver us? and truly being that your Higneſs hath ſeen, and we finde ſuch a prodigious <hi>omen</hi> to fall upon that day, we ought the more to acknowledge it, and to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve that the angels of God are come down to deliver us; and it is high time, all other hopes are gone now, for our enemies are potent, they have got all from us, Therefore from whence ſhould we look for help but from heaven?</p>
            <p>And leſt you ſhould ſay that we are popiſhly affected in worſhipping of angels, I ſay we wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip him onely whom the holy angels worſhip, even God who created all things, and his ſon <hi>Jeſus Chriſt,</hi> by whom he created all things, and the holy Ghoſt which ſanctifieth the whole cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ation; yet God forbid but that we ſhould have the holy Angels in great eſtimation for his ſake that ſends them, and for their works ſake, and for their own ſake, becauſe they are them which glorifie God in the higheſt degree; for if we are to have men in very high eſteem, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe they exhort us, 1 <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 5.12, 13. by how much more ought we to eſteem the Angels of God, ſent to do for us that which men cannot do for us; and truely we may err in the worſhip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:119980:11"/>of men, for they are vain-glorious, and apt to exact from us that reverence not due to them; but the Holy Angels are of another nature, ſo that we cannot err in that worſhip we do unto them, for they will tutor us ſo, that if we give unto them more then is meet, they will reprove us; therefore I ſay it is better, ſince we do not know the degrees of Angels, that we fall down flat before a Holy Angel, then ſtand againſt him, for all the Angels we read of, did not refuſe ſuch a worſhip, and who can tell which is the Angel of Gods preſence?</p>
            <p>And though that angel, <hi>Rev.</hi> 22.8, 9. did ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledge Saint <hi>John,</hi> inſomuch that he call<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed him his fellow-ſervant, and therefore would have no worſhip from him, he being as honor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able as himſelf, becauſe he was the beloved Apoſtle and Evangeliſt of <hi>Jeſus Christ;</hi> yet it is a queſtion, that if the ſame Angel at that time had been ſent to the Emperor of <hi>Rome,</hi> And that he had faln down before the Angel, whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther the Angel would not have taken it as a due worſhip from the Emperor, and yet deſtroy him with all his perſecuting hoaſt (as he did <hi>Senacheribs</hi>) except by repentance and amend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment they had prevented it.</p>
            <p>And truely thoſe people are in a ſad condi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, when the Angel of the Lord is ſent to per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecute them, <hi>Pſal.</hi> 35.5, 6. And they like <hi>Balaam</hi> going on ſtill, with their wicked intention, and cannot ſee the Angel with his drawn ſword, <hi>Numb.</hi> 22.22, 23. nor will not be <hi>admoniſhed.</hi> I have told the people of <hi>England</hi> (and ſpecially the chief of them) what they ſhould do, and what would follow, if they did it not. And now the Angel is come, my work is done, for he that
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:119980:12"/>is able to bring it to paſs, hath taken it off my hands.</p>
            <p>One aſs did reprove the madneſs of <hi>Balaam,</hi> 2 <hi>Pet.</hi> 2.15, 16. ſo that he ſaw the Angel of the <hi>Lord,</hi> and was ſaved from the preſent danger, <hi>Numb.</hi> 22.33. but the ſix horſes which ſaw the Angel, reproved the madneſs of this generati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and they will not ſee the Angel and repent. Oh miſerable men! do not you ſee the Scripture fulfilled (in this act of God?) how juſtly at this time may the Church of <hi>England</hi> (which you ſo perſecute) ſing the ſong of <hi>Moſes</hi> and of the Lamb? <hi>Exod.</hi> 15. <hi>Rev.</hi> 15.2, 3, 4. And what com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fort is it for them to ſee the Angel of the <hi>Lord</hi> engage for them, and encounter with their ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my! I am ſure it makes many glad heart.</p>
            <p>But what a joyful ſong ſhould we ſing, to ſee you return againe to the Church and the King! Oh it would be a joyful day to <hi>England;</hi> and ſince the Angels are become your adverſaries, we can expect no leſs, then to ſee either your ſud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dain return, or your ſuddain deſtruction. And who can help it, while ye go againſt God and his Church, and deprive your true and lawful King of all his right? Who dare petition to God for ſuch a people, that are reſolved not to repent of ſuch high inquity, that all the world rings of it? the ſin of <hi>Sodome</hi> was nothing to it, yet God came down purpoſely to deſtroy them poor igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant ſouls, and did it, and do you that have the Law and Goſpel to inſtruct you (commit ſuch evils, and) think to eſcape temporal and eternal puniſhment?</p>
            <p>What argument ſhall a man, that ſtands in the gap, bring before God when he prays for you? If he ſay with <hi>Abraham,</hi> Gen. 18.24. That
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:119980:12"/>peradventure there are ſome righteous perſons among you, your own declarations will tell him it is falſe.</p>
            <p>If with <hi>Moſes,</hi> Exod. 32.11, 12, 13. he menti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oneth an oath, or promiſe made to your fathers, alas what promiſe or oath can be alleadged (if there were any ſuch) on your <hi>behalf,</hi> that have broken ſo many oaths, and will not repent?</p>
            <p>If he ſay with Chriſt, <hi>Luk.</hi> 23.34. <hi>Father for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>give them, for they know not what they do;</hi> truly it is manifeſt you cannot be ſo ignorant.</p>
            <p>Therefore there is no going to God for you, but the onely way is to ſpeak to you, if ſo be you will hear and repent.</p>
            <p>Remember what our Saviour ſaith, <hi>Mat.</hi> 5.16. <hi>Let your light ſo ſhine before men, that they may ſee your good works, and glorifie your Father which is in heaven.</hi> It is not your confident notions in your ſpeech, nor the notions of them in the <hi>Memento</hi> to the Army, or in the Colonels pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tition, that will juſtifie you and them before God; nor is it your building upon your ſuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſes, as if God had owned you and your cauſe thereby; alas you come far ſhort in ſucceſſes to <hi>Alexander, Julius Caeſar, Mahumet,</hi> and many heatheniſh Commanders which had no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing of God in them, but rather the devil al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>together was the cauſe of it: therefore let not that deceive you.</p>
            <p>God will judge you according to your works, and men, angels, and all the world ſhall be your witneſs, you ſhall not be your own wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, and what you ſay for your ſelves is no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing of value, it being in your own cauſe.</p>
            <pb n="22" facs="tcp:119980:13"/>
            <p>Now it is for your juſtification to do ſuch works as all the world ſhall confeſs to be accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to Gods word: that they may bear witneſs to you, and ſay of a truth, theſe are the people of God, that is, for you to reſtore the King, then they will witneſs for you, but now they are wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs againſt you, inſomuch that they queſtion the juſtice of <hi>God</hi> for your ſake, ſaying, If Gods word be true, then theſe people, though they make ſuch a high profeſſion, and yet do as they do, and no puniſhment comes upon them, they are not the people of God. for thus they argue it with God:</p>
            <p>Is it poſſible that theſe are thy peculiar peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple that diſ-inherited their King (with all his ſeed, without the leaſt cauſe) of all his right which his predeceſſors enjoyed above two thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand yeers; And he by the whole conſent of the Nations put in poſſeſſion of it, under which King they lived ſo happy for many yeers, that all the world could not parallel, and for govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in Church &amp; State, there was not the like?</p>
            <p>Are theſe thy people, that when their King confiding in their fidelity to him, to be as true as his was to them, he knowing how deſerving he was of their loyalty, gave them more liberty then all the Kings that ever was before him did, to do what they would for the good of the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome, for them contrary to their oaths, to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy him and thy Church, and take all the <hi>patri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony</hi> to themſelves, belonging to thee and thy <hi>Church</hi> and Miniſters this thouſand yeers, and that took all from the loyal and conſcientious people? If theſe be thy people, then ſure the Scri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pture is not thy minde, and we are yet to ſeek.</p>
            <p>Oh <hi>Lord</hi> look upon thine honor: thy name is
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:119980:13"/>blaſphemed becauſe of theſe people, who call themſelves by thy name, and ſay what they did moſt wickedly, was thy works; laying it up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on thee to the diſhonor of thy name. Try them, ſee if any of them will prove ſo true to thee in their Religion, as <hi>Charles Steward,</hi> and <hi>William Laud</hi> did, alas they have no Religion, nor know they which to chuſe, but are confounded and divided, ſtriving who ſhall get moſt of their unrighteous <hi>Mammon</hi> gotten by oppreſſion.</p>
            <p>I believe I need not tell you (for you know it) that thus the world reſents you before God, ſhewing him that it is impoſſible for it to ſtand with his Holineſs, Juſtice, and Righteouſneſs, to let you go unpuniſhed: and conſider that God hath an high eſteem of his own name and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pute among all the world, and conſider that a Judge doth not (when an evidence is given a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt a malefactor) examine whether the <hi>wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſes</hi> be good men or bad: but if the witneſs agree, ſo that it is found that what they witneſs is true, the malefactor is condemned for his fault, though in other things he is more blame<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs then the witneſs.</p>
            <p>So when the cry againſt <hi>Sodom</hi> came up to heaven, it was not <hi>Lot</hi> nor <hi>Abrahams</hi> cry, for we ſee <hi>Abraham</hi> prayed for them, <hi>Gen.</hi> 18.27, 28. but it was the cry of the generality, that condem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned <hi>Sodom</hi> as wicked men, <hi>Gen.</hi> 13.13. And yet God makes as though he knew not the certainty of it, <hi>Gen.</hi> 18.20, 21. Therefore God ſends two angels to finde out the truth, and then to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy it, <hi>Gen.</hi> 19.1.12, 13. and how many angels were abuſed by you, we know not now ſince angels come in ſuch mean habits.</p>
            <p>Now after all this cry (about <hi>Sodom</hi>) it was
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:119980:14"/>not for Gods honor to let it ſtand: for what would men have ſaid, if he had not deſtroyed it; but conclude that God was the Author of all their wicked works? And how zealous is holy <hi>Moſes</hi> of the name of God, that the world ſhould not ſpeak evil of God for any cauſe, <hi>Numb.</hi> 14.11, 12, 13, 14.15, 16. And how ſevere did God puniſh <hi>David,</hi> becauſe he being re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported to be a man after Gods own heart, did give an occaſion for men to ſpeak evil of God? 2 <hi>Sam.</hi> 12.11, 12, 13, 14. for though <hi>David</hi> upon his repentance is quitted from death, yet the flower of his ſons muſt die for it, his wives are given before the eyes of all, to his own ſon, and he defiles them; and he purſueth his father <hi>Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vid</hi> to the death. Oh what a ſad condition was <hi>David</hi> in for that ſin? as you may ſee 2 <hi>Sam.</hi> 15. 2 <hi>Sam.</hi> 16. 2 <hi>Sam.</hi> 17. 2 <hi>Sam.</hi> 18.</p>
            <p>Therefore I beſeech you (as you tender your own ſalvation) have a care to the name of God, that you have taken upon you, before all the world, and let it not be evil ſpoken of for your ſake: methinks I hear the voice of <hi>Joſeph,</hi> Gen. 39.9. when his Miſtris tempted him to lie with her, ſaith he, <hi>My Maſter hath put all that he hath under mine hands, but thee, how then can I do this great wickedneſs vnd ſin againſt God?</hi> He was not to his maſter, as the late Parliament was to King <hi>Charles;</hi> he would rather go to priſon and die, then be ſo perfidious: but ſee the end of it; God exalts him, and makes him Lord over all <hi>Egypt,</hi> therefore have a care to the name of God. <hi>And let your light ſo ſhine before all the world, that they may ſee your good works, and glorifie your Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther which is in heaven;</hi> and this you can do no way, except by repentance you return to
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:119980:14"/>God, and reſtore King <hi>Charles,</hi> then all the world will ſay, that of a truth you are the Saints of God; and they will glorifie him on your be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half, for therein your deeds will appear to be righteous, and all good men whereſoever you go will joyn with you, and all the wicked will be ter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rified at the preſence of God with you, ſo that you ſhall conquer all afore you, and bring them under the Scepter of <hi>Jeſus Chriſt.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now providence hath ordered it, that you who are the moſt valiant, are in ſuch a condition, that it is not ſafe for you, nor honorable for King <hi>Charles</hi> and you to live together; Therefore God hath deſigned you for his battels abroad, and not to ſit ſtill at home, now you have done here, and quarrel one with another, but this you ſhall do, ſend to King <hi>Charles,</hi> that he may come to his throne, and deliver all unto him, except an Army for you to go forward, and means for ſo long a time, out of <hi>England</hi> to maintain it, and let King <hi>Charles</hi> have the Train<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band throughout the kingdome, ſettled under Colonels and Captaines to be ready at his call; for ſuch men have great intereſt belonging to them, as well as the King hath, and are able to maintain themſelves in ſervice if need require; therefore let all rich and landed ſufficient men bear arms for their King and their own ſafety: you know the people of Iſrael were in ſuch a poſture, and all from <hi>Dan</hi> to <hi>Beerſheba</hi> roſe as one man, when an enemy appeared: and there was no taxing.</p>
            <p>What ſhal we do with any other ſtanding <hi>army</hi> here, except it be for our Governors to enſlave us thereby? therefore take your <hi>commiſſions</hi> from King <hi>Charles,</hi> or uſe thoſe Commiſſions that you
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:119980:15"/>have, as if they were from him, or from his father, who indeed is the fountain of them; and you ſhall finde you will do better abroad then at home; and you will have great comfort in God, and proſperity abroad, when you are at peace with your King, and act by vertue of his power, it being Gods Ordinance for you to obſerve: and let your deſign in the firſt place be, to ſet the Jews in their own land, and be the means to convert them to <hi>Jeſus Chriſt;</hi> ſure<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly then you ſhall ſee more of God, then yet you have ſeen.</p>
            <p>And whereas it was affirmed among us at the beginning of theſe times by the Presbyterians, from <hi>Pſal.</hi> 105.15. 1 <hi>Chro.</hi> 16.22. that all the peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple of God were <hi>anointed,</hi> and that they were <hi>the anointed</hi> (the <hi>King</hi> was no body to them) and that they ſhould binde Kings in Chaines, and Nobles in Iron fetters, <hi>Pſal.</hi> 149. and exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute upon the earth the judgement that was written; and then forſooth we termed our ſelves Saints, &amp; roſe againſt our K. to begin with him; when indeed nature would have taught us, if we had not been more fools then Saints, to let him been the laſt; and them that would not riſe a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the King, their Miniſters curſed them with the curſe of <hi>Meroz,</hi> Judg. 5.23.</p>
            <p>Oh how did the Kings then laugh at our folly in giving out, That we would conquer all the Kings before us; for they knew that ſuch a con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ed multitude without a head, could never hurt them, for the <hi>Pſalmiſt</hi> ſaith, <hi>Pſal.</hi> 76.12. <hi>He is terrible to the Kings of the earth;</hi> therefore the Saints can do nothing untill they be united, and have a Commiſſion from King <hi>Charles,</hi> and upon that account they ſhall have enough to
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:119980:15"/>joyn with them, and aſſiſt them. Then let the mocking Kings be wiſe and kiſs King <hi>Charles,</hi> leſt they ſmart for their folly, <hi>Pſal.</hi> 2.10, 11, 12. For <hi>God hath ſent the hornet among them already,</hi> Exo. 23.28. Joſh. 24.12. The Lord by me hath blown the trumpet before you; for I am ſure my books are gone over all Europe to that purpoſe, and had free paſſage by Gods providence; for had the King and you been agreed before now, my <hi>books</hi> could not have ſo free a paſſage as they had among foraign Nations; and I am ſure it takes a great impreſſion on them: and when the King and you agree, my books will be called in, and then it will take more impreſſion, and turn the moſt part in all places for you, and the Jews from all parts will come to you, for they wait for ſuch an appearance, and have my books to aſſure them further of it.</p>
            <p>And will it not be a happy thing to ſee them come in to <hi>Jeſus Christ?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Oh for <hi>Christs</hi> ſake, and for the <hi>Jews</hi> ſake, who are them from whence we had the Oracles of God, let neither fear, nor any other thing hinder you from making agreement with King <hi>Charles;</hi> do not hinder Gods deſign to ſave the Jews: and as <hi>Mordecai</hi> once ſaid upon the like occaſion, ſo ſay I now to you, and conclude, <hi>Esth.</hi> 4.13, 14. <hi>Think not with thy ſelf, that thou ſhalt eſcape in the kings houſe more then all the Jews; for if thou altogether holdeſt thy peace at this time, then ſhall there be enlargement and deliverance ariſe to the Jews from another place, but thou and thy fathers houſe ſhall be deſtroyed; and who knoweth whether thou art come to the kingdome for ſuch a time as this?</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
         <div type="postscript">
            <pb facs="tcp:119980:16"/>
            <head>A deſperate diſeaſe muſt have a de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſperate cure.</head>
            <head type="sub">Or, a Poſtſcript to the Book.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>THere is a certain portion of phyſick found out of late, called the Antimonial cup, or</hi> Evans <hi>his cup, in regard one</hi> Evans <hi>(as they ſay) was the firſt ſounder of it. And this cup is ſuch a deſperate phyſick, that immediately it either kills or cures thoſe that take it. If it works with them, though by the judgement of the Phyſitian they be paſt hopes, whatſoever diſeaſe they have, it will reſtore them to their perfect health; but if it will not work with them, then it quickly ends them. This I thought good to ſet down, for I know God hath ſent that cup as an emblem of this cup, which I now preſent to the politick body of theſe ſick nations: firſt, becauſe of the effects of it, and then becauſe his name that found it was</hi> Evans: <hi>and truely the meſſage of God, is of the ſame effect, for where it worketh, ſo that it is believed and obeyed, it is the ſavor of life unto life, and to the other that believe not, it is the ſavor of death unto death,</hi> 2 Cor. 2.15, 16. <hi>ſo that the cup being</hi> Evans, <hi>ſignifies the meſſenger, and the effects of it being to heal or kill, ſignifies the meſſage of God to you.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>The prophet</hi> Jeremiah <hi>once had a cup of fury from the Lord, and all the Nations to which God ſends him, were unavoidably to drink of it,</hi> Jer. 25.15, 16, 17.27, 28, 29. <hi>but I truſt this cup will work with
<pb facs="tcp:119980:16"/>you my Lord, ſo that it will be a cup of ſalvation to you; and how meet are theſe words for you to ſpeak when you take it,</hi> Pſal. 116.12, 13, 14. What ſhall I render unto the Lord for all his benefits to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards me? I will take the cup of ſalvation and call upon the name of the Lord: I will pay my vows <hi>(that is, your vows made to the King and Church)</hi> unto the Lord now in the preſence of all his people; <hi>And if it prove otherways with you my Lord, I ſhall be ſorry for you, becauſe I fear your houſe will not ſtand.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Men by their policy may come in time to loſe them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves: you know</hi> Jeroboam <hi>had a promiſe from God, that if he did walk in the wayes of</hi> David <hi>(that is, in his Religion) then God would build him a ſure houſe,</hi> 1 Kings 11.38. <hi>but</hi> Jeroboam <hi>thought as you think now, that if the government by Biſhops (as heretofore) ſhall be eſtabliſhed here again; then it will be a means to draw the people to their right King again. So</hi> Jeroboam <hi>thinking to prevent that, deviſeth a Religion out of his own heart, ſets up gol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den Calves for the people to worſhip,</hi> 1 Kin. 12.26, 27, 28, 29, 30, 31, 32, 33. <hi>caſteth out all the ſons of</hi> Aaron <hi>from being Miniſters,</hi> 2 Chron. 11.13, 14, 15. 2 Chron. 13.8.19. <hi>but the Lord ſtrikes him dead for it,</hi> 2 Chron. 13.20. <hi>and deſtroyed all that he had,</hi> 1 King. 15.19. <hi>Thus</hi> Jeroboam <hi>was deceived, and ſo are you in that point; for if</hi> Jeroboam <hi>had gone to worſhip at Jeruſalem, and walked in the wayes of</hi> David, <hi>queſtionleſs his houſe had ſtood, and he might have lived with</hi> Rehoboam <hi>quiety. There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the beſt way for you, is to eſtabliſh the Church as it was, for then will the generality of your ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies turn to you, ſo that the King and you may come to an agreement, though you ſhould have the greateſt ſhare in the government of the Nations.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:119980:17"/>
            <p>
               <hi>My Lord I am ambitious with a holy ambition, I would faine be more then conqueror,</hi> Rom. 8.37. <hi>and bring you into ſubjection for your own good: it is better for you to yeild unto me, then to contend with the Angel of the Lord that is ready to ſecond me:</hi> Pharaoh <hi>was riſed up of God, to be the object of his judgement, that the power and glory of his juſtice might be made known upon the earth, therefore he hardned</hi> Pharaohs <hi>heart,</hi> Rom. 9.17, 18. <hi>but I hope God hath raiſed you up, to be the object of his love, that the power and glory of his mercy might be made known upon the earth; and therefore he will ſoften your heart to receive theſe things: ſo be it.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Ariſe Evans.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:119980:17"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
